<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Isaac Khor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://isaackhor.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Isaac Khor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2016 Isaac Khor.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 14:57:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://isaackhor.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Killing Project Duodecimal</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2017/killing-project-duodecimal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 14:57:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2017/killing-project-duodecimal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the Clarentine calendar was based on divisions of twelve, I thought it would be a good idea to notate all numbers in duodecimal. This was part of a larger internal effort in my life, aptly called Project Duodecimal, to convert all numbers I interact with to duodecimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after much consideration, I have come to the conclusion that due to the sheer momentum of decimal number notation, changing all numbers I interact with to duodecimal will be using far too much effort relative to the possible gains. Most of the world runs on decimal, uses divisions of ten, and is not compatible with a duodecimal system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has led me to abandon Project Duodecimal; despite being one of my oldest projects, its priority has always been one of the lowest, so not much progress has been made. There are &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; specifications for a new duodecimal system, along with notation and names similar to metric prefixes, but due to their underdevelopment, I will be not be releasing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, most of the advantages of using twelve as the base of my calendar are still preserved even if I switch the &lt;em&gt;notation&lt;/em&gt; over to decimal. So, divisions in the Clarentine calendar are still made of twelve units, but the notation for dates will change slightly to accommodate the new decimal notation. I am still working on how to best fit these numbers into a single consistent date format; the next version of the specification should be published soon with this notation overhaul along with some changes to names.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Clarentine Calendar Explained</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2017/the-clarentine-calendar-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 18:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2017/the-clarentine-calendar-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A note on notation: all numbers are in base-twelve unless it ends with a e, which means it is in decimal or base-ten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Clarentine Calendar that I recently published contains a number of &amp;hellip; interesting &amp;hellip; systems, the most notable of which is the usage of base-twelve and the ignoring of the conventional 265/365e year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for using duodecimal has been mentioned by many before me; I will not repeat them again.  If you are too lazy to find out, it basically boils down to composability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t even try to incorporate the traditional 265 day cycle into the calendar is because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.  I don&amp;rsquo;t care about needing the calendar to keep track of the seasons for me, which is, as far as I can tell, the main reason for a solar calendar in the first place.  If I needed to know the current season, I can always look out of the window, or in the case here in Malaysia, remain blissfully ignorant of any seasons at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t care how far along Earth is along its rotation around the Sun; I sleep just as well at night not knowing this information.  A rational system of dividing time matters far more to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other notable feature of the calendar is its usage of &lt;em&gt;subdivisions&lt;/em&gt;.  Subdivisions exist because of how I structure my life: I have certain tasks that I do every 3, 4, and 6 days, which are perfectly aligned with these subdivisions.  These are the fundamental units of time that I work with beyond the single day; it makes sense to incorporate them into my personal calendar as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice of the J2000 epoch was arbitrary; it&amp;rsquo;s close enough to my lifetime to have the years in fairly low numbers, and has a nice compatibility with UTC that functions just like the Unix 1 Jan 1970e epoch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still working on a better way to notate the difference between absolute and relative dates; adding a &amp;lsquo;y&amp;rsquo; in the middle of the string looks ugly.  However, I consider the overall &lt;em&gt;structure&lt;/em&gt; of the calendar complete; the naming and some small details might change, but the overall layout of the calendar should be final.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem with Audiobooks</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2017/the-problem-with-audiobooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2017/the-problem-with-audiobooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Audiobooks, in theory, are a great idea: have somebody read the thing you were going to read to yourself out loud, and you can listen to it while doing something else, like cooking, cleaning, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the passive version of reading: information flows from the text into your brain, with no interruptions, and not requiring a lot of engagement from the reader. That, however, is not how &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I read, I jump around. A lot. When I realise that the paragraph I am reading can be skipped, I do so. When I am confused, I jump back. I skim, jump forward, reread, jump back, pause to process the information, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to the first 3 hours of &lt;em&gt;Guns, Germs, and Steel&lt;/em&gt;, and then reading the second half, just made me realise how much I &lt;em&gt;skip&lt;/em&gt; while reading a book, and how much I go back and reread, with pauses along the way to think about the author&amp;rsquo;s arguments and see if they make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a well-known fact that I consume all media at 2-4x speed, depending on the thing in question, and this book is no different. Most of the time, at 3x speed, the narrator is speaking at a comfortable pace for me. However, I have to listen to him read the parts that I would have skipped, which makes me stop paying attention and leaves me confused when I inevitably start paying attention, only to find the narrator somewhere completely new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pausing is also a pain with audiobooks. For most of the books I read, which are mostly the author trying to present an argument, which, at a glance, is about three quarters of my reading list, I need to pause frequently and think about the author&amp;rsquo;s argument, and let myself have some time to digest it. The set pace of narration destroys my frequent reflections, and I have found that after 1 hour of GGS, or 3 hours into the book, I felt myself not really &lt;em&gt;understanding&lt;/em&gt; the argument being presented. The last half of the book took me an hour to read, which tells me that it&amp;rsquo;s not the &lt;em&gt;speed&lt;/em&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s the problem, it&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;em&gt;manner&lt;/em&gt; of information digestion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this is to say that my time with audiobooks have ended; I will never again listen to audiobooks, for they do not accomplish the goal of reading books in the first place: to understand the author&amp;rsquo;s argument and decide if it is valid. Reading words on a paper remains the only way to do so for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox 50 Extensions</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2017/firefox-50-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 20:22:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2017/firefox-50-extensions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;About four months after my switch to Firefox, my extensions situation seems to have finally stabilised. Thus, it&amp;rsquo;s time to take a comprehensive inventory of my entire browser system, for the sake of documentation in case I need to set up this system again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to still be using this in a year, but with Firefox extensions, you will never know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ui-enhancements&#34;&gt;UI Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tab Centre:&lt;/strong&gt; Tabs laid out vertically makes much more sense that the default horizontal configuration. The main reason is that I don&amp;rsquo;t like to have wide browser windows, since most webpages utilise &lt;em&gt;vertical&lt;/em&gt; rather than &lt;em&gt;horizontal&lt;/em&gt; space, and having tabs laid out vertically makes it easier for me to find everything anyways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reddit Enhancement Suite:&lt;/strong&gt; Self-explanatory. Browsing reddit without RES drives me insane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1Password:&lt;/strong&gt; While not strictly a purely UI addon, I will include it here anyways. My username and password system is beyond the scope of this article; all you need to know is that everything is managed through 1Password (along with some scripts I hacked together).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DevEdition theme enabler:&lt;/strong&gt; The default theme looks ugly. What more can I say?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy&#34;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;uBlock Origin:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, I run an adblocker, and yes, it is not purely for privacy reasons. I used to use AdBlock, but as many others have discovered, uBlock is the best when it comes to CPU and memory usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghostery:&lt;/strong&gt; I am actually experimenting with removing Ghostery, since the things it blocks should already be included in uBlock, but it stays for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Destructing Cookies:&lt;/strong&gt; I used to maintain a cookie whitelist, but I have found that to be &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; to much work; setting certain websites to have their cookies kept with SDC is a system that is just as practical and requires almost no work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NoScript:&lt;/strong&gt; JavaScript-blocking is a must. I don&amp;rsquo;t trust most websites enough to run their code on my machine, and most pages work just fine without JS anyways. I am pretty strict with enabling JavaScript, and even with that most websites still work just fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentraleyes:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a local CDN cache that requires very little maintenance, and is here for no reason other than it provides &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; protection against fingerprinting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random Agent Spoofer:&lt;/strong&gt; This extension, as it name suggests, spoofs the UserAgent that your browser sends; it is a great protection against browser fingerprinting. It also includes some options for countering other forms of fingerprinting, like disabling JS canvas support, some of which are enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTPS Everywhere:&lt;/strong&gt; Despite my misgivings about the EFF, this remains a must-have extension, since I don&amp;rsquo;t like MiTM attacks, and neither should you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;utilities&#34;&gt;Utilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dorando keyconfig:&lt;/strong&gt; This extension is for binding shortcuts to Firefox, since it uses a custom keyboard event-handling system that is opaque and extremely hard to configure. I have just recently started playing with Hammerspoon, and I am currently experimenting with removing this extension and migrating my shortcuts over to Hammerspoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test pilot:&lt;/strong&gt; Dependency for Tab Center; I can&amp;rsquo;t remove it even if I wanted to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add-on Compatibility Reporter:&lt;/strong&gt; Temporary while I puzzle over the migration to e10s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Clarentine Calendar</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/the-clarentine-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 21:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/the-clarentine-calendar/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I just designed a new calendar! The first draft has been copied here; for the most recent version, check it out on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/IsaacKhor/project-clarentine/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-clarentine-calendar&#34;&gt;The Clarentine Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the formal specification for the Clarentine calendar. This document is a &lt;em&gt;work is progress&lt;/em&gt;, it will change as feedback is incorporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All pronunciations shall follow the rules of Standard Clarentine English Pronunciation (will be published later; it&amp;rsquo;s still a work in progress).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: all numbers are written in base 10d/12e, or base-twelve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;day&#34;&gt;Day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental unit of time in the Clarentine Calendar is the &lt;em&gt;day&lt;/em&gt;. A day is defined they same way as in the UTC, including leap seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;divisions-of-time&#34;&gt;Divisions of Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two &lt;em&gt;types&lt;/em&gt; of time periods: a &lt;strong&gt;division&lt;/strong&gt;, and a &lt;strong&gt;subdivision&lt;/strong&gt;. Divisions are converted to each other at a 1:10 ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;divisions&#34;&gt;Divisions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Plural&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Postfix form&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Composed of&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Day&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Days&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;dies&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;UTC day&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Months&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;menses&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 days&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;anni&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 months&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;subdivisions&#34;&gt;Subdivisions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Prefix&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Number of divisions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;tri-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;quad-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;hex-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 days = 1 tridie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 days = 1 quadie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 days = 1 hexdie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 days = 1 month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 months = 1 trimenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 months = 1 quadmenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 months = 1 hexmenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 months = 1 year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;epoch&#34;&gt;Epoch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This calendar uses the &amp;ldquo;J2000&amp;rdquo; epoch. The date 0-00 11:58:55.816 is defined as J2000, or 1 January 2000 11:58:55.816 UTC, or 1 January 2000 11:59:27.816 TAI (UTC and TAI times in decimal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notation&#34;&gt;Notation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;y*-md&amp;rdquo;, where &amp;ldquo;y*&amp;rdquo; is the year to as many digits as needed, &amp;ldquo;m&amp;rdquo; the month, and &amp;ldquo;d&amp;rdquo; the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All numbers are filled into the template from right-to-left, from the least significant to the most significant. All missing numbers are assumed to be the current division of time. The hyphen between the year and the month/day can be left out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;42 : Current year, month 4, day 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-56 : Current 10-year, year 3, month 5, day 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1234-78 : Current 10000-year, year 1234, month 7, day 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9ab: Current 10-year (and all above), year 9, month A, day B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stories That We Tell Ourselves - Meditations 2</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/the-stories-that-we-tell-ourselves---meditations-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 18:58:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/the-stories-that-we-tell-ourselves---meditations-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I live by the philosophy of Nihilism: nothing has any inherent meaning. The most frequent question I get when I tell this to other people, however, is this: if life is meaningless, why live it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My usual response is something like this: life is just as meaningless as death; this is the only time I&amp;rsquo;ll live, so I might as well take advantage of it. Life has no value; if I felt like the cost of living longer does not outweigh the benefits, then I can stop living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That, however, is not the real answer. Yes, it is technically correct, but it is not the &lt;em&gt;whole&lt;/em&gt; answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer lies behind the workings of the human brain. We know, for example, that we are not evolutionarily attuned to the &lt;em&gt;truth&lt;/em&gt;, but to nature&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;fitness function&lt;/em&gt;. For all we know, the concept of &lt;em&gt;truth&lt;/em&gt; itself may be fundamentally flawed, and if that is the case, all of our philosophy might as well get thrown out of the window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;whole&lt;/em&gt; answer is this: all of our belief systems, be it Christianity, Zen Buddhism, Islam, Nihilism, or whatever beliefs you might hold, these are all just &lt;em&gt;stories&lt;/em&gt; that we tell ourselves to make us live through our life better. Nature doesn&amp;rsquo;t care what we believe as long as we make babies; you can believe that a Jewish Zombie has saved you, or that a guy rode off on a flying horse, but both of you can still live on the same planet and interact with each other as normal human beings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as everybody lives along fine and produces enough babies, all of these belief systems will persist. The stories that we tell ourselves are just that: &lt;em&gt;stories&lt;/em&gt;. The universe doesn&amp;rsquo;t care if it has any validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Christian friends find comfort in the &lt;em&gt;fact&lt;/em&gt; that a cosmic Jewish Zombie, whom they have telepathically accepted as their master, has removed an evil force from their soul that&amp;rsquo;s there because a rib-women ate a magical apple on the advice of a talking snake (shamelessly copied from ED). The suicide bombers of the extreme Islamists die a happy death &lt;em&gt;knowing&lt;/em&gt; that they will be handsomely rewarded for the service by their almighty deity in their afterlife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, similarly, find &lt;em&gt;comfort&lt;/em&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;lack&lt;/em&gt; of life after death, and the lack of a meaning of life. I feel comforted by the lack of absolute morality and am relieved by my ability to end my miserable existence as I see fit. I find freedom in the lack of meaning and the lack of eternal existence. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to exist forever; the fact that some day, I will &lt;em&gt;cease&lt;/em&gt; to exist, comforts me, just like it does for the Buddhists seeking &lt;em&gt;Nirvana&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also come to find comfort in our inability to understand the universe. Are all the patterns we see just patterns &lt;em&gt;made&lt;/em&gt; by our pattern-seeking brains? Is everything material? Does the question even make sense? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, and I never will. There is comfort to be found in our lack of answers, and in our lack of ability to &lt;em&gt;understand it all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The realisation that all belief systems are just stories that are told to the brain has &lt;em&gt;freed&lt;/em&gt; me from my quest to seek out &lt;em&gt;the best belief system&lt;/em&gt;; they are equally valid, and as long as you continue to live, their job has been accomplished. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that I am not open to change; I will readily abandon my beliefs if a new system that helps make the brain happier is found. I hold beliefs not because they are &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt;, but because they are &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This realisation, for me, has made the world a tremendously happier place. As long as everybody&amp;rsquo;s interpretations of their world render them a functional human being, the interpretation itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I don&amp;rsquo;t care if you believe that you have been saved by a cosmic Jewish Zombie; if you are a pleasant human being to interact with, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. The belief of others matters much less than my interaction with them; does this not make interaction with others that much more pleasant?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MUN - The Game of Politics</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/mun---the-game-of-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 22:49:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/mun---the-game-of-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There has recently been talk amongst the school about starting a Model United Nations programme. As perhaps the only person at the school that has any experience with this area, I feel an obligation to chime in and give my two cents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, you must know what MUN is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;. It is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a chance to debate policy. It is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a simulation of the actual UN sitting in NYC. It is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a forum where people come together to have intellectual discussions on pressing political issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What MUN &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;, however, is a place where you get to practise your skills in &lt;em&gt;politics&lt;/em&gt;. It is a forum where you see how the house of cards that is politics play out. This is where, if you are observant, you learn the skills that will aid you in becoming a good politician: behind-the-scenes bargaining, mass-persuasion, power blocs, identification of the keys figures and negotiating with them, speeches that persuade by &lt;em&gt;words&lt;/em&gt;, not logic, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going to MUN to hone your debating skills, turn back now. That is the last thing that you will find. MUN is a byzantine collection of rules and tradition that is in no way conducive of debates. You, if you have points to make and arguments to rebut, will find yourself unable to do either. MUN is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a forum of debate. You must get your talking done &lt;em&gt;through other people&lt;/em&gt;, which is where the game of politics comes into play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going to MUN to see what the actual UN is like, you too should turn back now. Just compare footage of the UN General Assembly meetings with any MUN footage you can find. Those two things are not the same. The actual UN&amp;rsquo;s goal is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to pass more resolutions since they all know that those don&amp;rsquo;t do anything. However, passing resolutions &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the ultimate goal for a MUN conference; and because of that, the structure and politics of these two organisations play out very differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about what happens in a MUN conference. As I said, the ultimate goal here is to pass resolutions. To do that, you need a majority vote (unlike the UN where most resolutions are passed by consensus), and to get those votes, politics needs to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary way of changing people&amp;rsquo;s mind on voting for or against your resolution is speeches. A person goes up to the podium, gives a speech, and answers some questions. However, one man cannot pass resolutions alone. The chair won&amp;rsquo;t let you speak that many times. This is why I said that you need to speak &lt;em&gt;through other people&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where all that politics that I talked about comes into play: some people are better persuaders than others. These are the individuals that have the ability to sway many voters to their side. These are the individuals that give 95% of the speeches, ask the majority of questions, and exert the most influence over their mindless peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are observant, you will see these persuaders forming alliances early in the conference. Some are not aware that they are doing so, due to their innate ability to play the game of politics, but some are much more deliberate, like me. These alliances are not formal: most times, there isn&amp;rsquo;t even a verbal agreement. It&amp;rsquo;s a non-explicit mutual understanding that, instead of doing their best to bring you down, they will assist or at the very least not actively hinder you in passing your resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In MUN, most voters are merely mindless automatons. They are passive agents, a pawn in the game of Chess the select few persuaders are playing. Ask any experienced MUN-er about their experience at MUN, at the first thing you will find out is that 10% of the speakers give 90% of the speeches and hold 99% of the power. Most voters do not evaluate the merits of both sides of the resolution and vote by the rules of logic; most are bound by the limits of human psychology and act accordingly. You win votes by &lt;em&gt;sounding&lt;/em&gt; right, not by &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; right. Of course, in order to fight the battle with other persuaders, logic is a tool that can make your opponent &lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; like they don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are doing. Here lies the most important distinction: logic is not &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt; the component that persuades, it is the &lt;em&gt;illusion&lt;/em&gt; it gives of authority and correctness that persuades. Logic doesn&amp;rsquo;t persuade, &lt;em&gt;words&lt;/em&gt; persuade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mindless automaton theory only applies to large committees, in smaller committees, where schools send their veterans, the tools of persuasion no longer applies, which in turn increases the importance of alliances and politics. However, as a newcomer, your chances of making it into the smaller elite committees are close to nil, mainly due to your lack of political experience, so you need not concern yourself with them for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself disgusted at the nature of human psychology and the game of politics, MUN will not suit you well, unless you intend on playing the part of the mindless automaton. If you think you will enjoy the mindless automaton experience, by all means, join MUN. If you can, try to pay attention to the game of politics and intrigue that is playing out around you; it may become useful if you decide to try playing the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself excited at the idea of weaving political webs and playing the game of persuasion, MUN will suit you well. Once you see MUN for what it really is, instead of what it claims to be, it will become a very enjoyable experience. There is no thrill like realising that your plan to use the tools of persuasion actually sways others to your banner. In that case, I wish you the very best. Enjoy your time with the politics of MUN.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thoughts Floating In My Head - Meditations 1</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/random-thoughts-floating-in-my-head---meditations-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 22:03:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/random-thoughts-floating-in-my-head---meditations-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting from today, I will be forcing myself to write an essay fortnightly in an effort to improve my writing. The contents of these essays will range wildly from programming to politics and philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These essays are meant to be for me and me only, hence the name: meditations, inspired by the Roman philosopher-king Marcus Aurelius&amp;rsquo; untitled works commonly referred to as the &lt;em&gt;Meditations&lt;/em&gt;. If you are reading this, I welcome your feedback, but please understand if nothing makes sense. They exist for the sole purpose of benefiting me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my initial exposure to philosophy and scepticism, my worldview has been in a constant state of flux. My religious views have shifted from Christianity to agnosticism, then finally to atheism, which I still believe as of the time of writing; my philosophical outlook has shifted from a conservative Christian one taught by my parents to secular humanism to relativism finally to a blend between nihilism and some other beliefs that don&amp;rsquo;t have specific labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout all of this transition, I have never been able to form a full picture of my current beliefs. All of my beliefs are compartmentalised into their own little world with vague interactions with all others, where a grand unifying framework upon which all of them rest doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This complex system of individual beliefs without connection to others is a remnant of the slow and gradual development of these ideas over time, building upon several different sources at different points of my life. While meandering through the tomes of philosophical knowledge, I would occasionally stumble across an idea with which I agree or an argument that I found persuasive, and change my belief by a tiny bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, my beliefs have fragmented into a thousand tiny kingdoms, each with their own system and customs, all standing alone, isolated from each other. Some ideas lie in conflict with each other, some stand alone in a corner, abstraction nowhere to be seen. Some are remnants of a long-gone age when my young, naive self found himself persuaded by long-forgotten arguments and changed his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like a tipping point has been reached; for too long have these isolated ideas stood by themselves, it is time for an attempt, however arduous and futile it may be, to reconcile these ideas on a larger scale, time for these ideas to form higher-level frameworks for which they can rest upon. My brain cannot simultaneously account for hundreds if not thousands of individual little pieces of information, they must be built into larger units that I can reason about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve this goal, I must begin by cataloguing what beliefs I hold. Hence the need for these essays: they provide a concrete means of listing in detail what I believe and how I got there (assuming I still remember the reasons), and from there, once I have a better understanding of the landscape of my brain, only can I begin restructuring and refactoring (it&amp;rsquo;s a programming term; google it) said beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how long this will take, nor do I know what the results of this journey will be. All I know is that my brain cannot simultaneously hold a thousand belief systems together, and that something must change so that I will not have to try. So begins a new chapter in my philosophical journey: a period of consolidation and reorganisation. Wish me luck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 ISKL Forensics Competition - Original Oratory Entry</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/2016-iskl-forensics-competition---original-oratory-entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 16:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/2016-iskl-forensics-competition---original-oratory-entry/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My Original Oratory entry for the 2016 ISKL forensics competition, published here in its full glory. Yes, I know, it is really, really, really bad, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to put it up here anyways for the sake of letting other people learn from my mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;daylight-saving-time&#34;&gt;Daylight Saving Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daylight saving time, making timezones confusing since 1916. If you are not familiar with it, daylight saving time is a weird ritual in which countries move their clocks forward sometime in the spring, only to move them back sometime in the fall. To the rest of the world that doesn’t participate in this biannual ritual of clock fiddling, it might seem like a baffling thing to do. After all, clocks are fine the way they are, why change them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original idea, proposed by George Hudson, had nothing to do with saving daylight and everything to do with catching butterflies. He thought that if clocks were shifted forward in the summer, he would get more time after work to indulge in his hobby of catching butterflies. Of course, “butterfly catching time” is not exactly a sexy name that will get you votes, so he renamed it daylight saving time and sold it as a way to conserve daylight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Germany, the first country to implement the system, did so because they needed more coal to fuel their efforts in World War I. The reasoning is that if the population woke up later and slept later, they will use less artificial light, freeing up coal for the war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While that might have worked in 1916, does it still work in the modern world of 2016? As it turns out, this is a surprisingly hard question to answer. There is no consensus in the scientific community, with some studies claiming it does save energy and some studies claiming the exact opposite. But, the studies all agree on one thing: how little energy you save or lose. It is not 10 percent, it’s not 5%, it’s 1 percent. 1 whole percent of an increase or decrease in your energy bill. That’s about 4 dollars annually, which is not even enough for a cup of coffee, so we might as well ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since daylight saving time’s energy savings are nonexistent, and most people don’t care about catching butterflies, should we we keep the biannual ritual of clock fiddling around? Unlike the previous energy problem, the research on this is very clear: no, clock fiddling causes more problems that it solves, if it solves any at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most obvious problem comes from sleep deprivation. Waking up an hour earlier generally causes you to sleep less, and sleep deprivation has been shown to lead to heart attacks and suicides. Researchers have found that in the days following the time change there is a 10 percent increase in heart attacks and suicides. We are literally killing people by fiddling with clocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem comes from scheduling meetings across time zones. Let’s say that you want to plan a conference between New York, London, and Sydney, which will be fun because none of the three agree on when to start and end daylight saving time. During the spring, in the space of 3 weeks, New York is 5 hours behind London, then 4, then 5 hours again, depending on the week, Sydney is either 11, 10, or 9 hours away from New York, and Sydney is again either 16, 15, or 14 hours from London. I know, I wrote this myself, and even I am confused. And the whole thing will happen again, just in reverse, when autumn comes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is madness! It might have not mattered 100 years ago in the Dark Ages of no internet, but, in 2016, where thousands international meetings are planned every single day, shifting around time zones isn’t going to do anybody any favours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, you might be wondering: wait, so how does this daylight saving thing work? We remove an hour from the day in the spring and add an hour in the fall - but, what does it actually look like on my clock? I’m glad you asked, because the solution is very … clever. So clever, in fact, that no clocks on the planet can actually accomplish such a feat. Our excellent governments decided for some reason that the best way to remove an hour from the day is to skip 2 am. During the spring, the official clock will go 1:57, 1:58, 1:59, 3:00. During the fall, to add an hour to the day, 1 am is repeated, and the official clocks go 1:57, 1:58, 1:59, 1:00. Surely all clocks on the planet can achieve such an easy task. I don’t know about you, but I have never in my life seen the hour hand on my watch jump from 1 to 3. In fact, I am pretty sure that it can’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What then? The clock fiddling advocate tells us to replace all clocks with digital clocks that have wireless chips in them to connect to the internet to update their time. I am sure that you can find some flaws in this line of reasoning, like &amp;ndash; how do you tell your clock your wifi password? You can’t expect a tiny computer to run on battery power for a whole year. So, who gets the power? Your phone or clock? I can go on forever about the problems, but I only have so much time. Unless they add an hour in the middle of my speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To review, daylight saving time saves almost no energy, causes sleep deprivation, causes more suicides, makes planning international meetings an absolute joy, terrorises the twenty-four hour day, and trashes the non-internet-savvy clock. This is why we should get rid of it, to make timezones normal and less confusing again. Let us restore the former glory of timezones as they were before that dreadful day in 1916. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Post</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/initial-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 19:48:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/blog/2016/initial-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After endless hours of fiddling around with CSS and Hugo templates, this website finally looks half-decent! Let&amp;rsquo;s just all pretend that the thing that used to be here never existed, and carry on with our day. I will write more about setting this place up later, I need to make sure deployment to Github Pages works correctly first.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Nothing interesting here other than random essays by Isaac Khor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-can-you-describe-your-workflow-in-publishing-an-article&#34;&gt;1. Can you describe your workflow in publishing an article?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new blog/post-name.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete everything and start over again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat from #2 until it&amp;rsquo;s half-decent to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add -all; git commit -m &amp;quot;New post: post name&amp;quot;; git push&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-what-programming-languages-do-you-use&#34;&gt;2. What programming languages do you use?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clojure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common Lisp (a lot less frequently than a year ago, but I still use it occasionaly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java (only if I have to do some tricky interfacing between Scala and Clojure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C#&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-who-are-your-favourite-composers&#34;&gt;3. Who are your favourite composers?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Franz Listz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Johannes Brahms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude Debussy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Hindemith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Strauss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guillaume Lekeu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-i-just-looked-at-the-website-source-it-belongs-on-thedailywtf-http-thedailywtf-com&#34;&gt;4. I just looked at the website source. It belongs on &lt;a href=&#34;http://thedailywtf.com&#34;&gt;TheDailyWTF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not a question.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know me personally or know somebody that does, the easiest way of contacting me is via email (It&amp;rsquo;s an image because I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure spambot crawlers don&amp;rsquo;t do OCR):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://isaackhor.com/img/contact.png&#34; alt=&#34;Email address&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the response time that I strive to achieve given the method of communication:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone number: one hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People already in my contacts: one day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social media &amp;amp; the email shown above: 3 days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add a day if the reply takes a long time to compose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://isaackhor.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaackhor.com/license/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Copyright &amp;copy; 2016 Isaac Khor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All content on this site, unless otherwise noted, is under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International license. For the full license, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/legalcode&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All source code, unless otherwise noted, is copyrighted under GPL 3.0. For the full license, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0-standalone.html&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme is based heavily on Ochiishi Koichiro&amp;rsquo;s theme &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-zen/&#34;&gt;Hugo Zen&lt;/a&gt;, licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;MIT license&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog uses code from &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;, which is licensed under the MIT license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is powered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>